<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on JSvdW Hugo test</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on JSvdW Hugo test</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/assessment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/assessment/</guid><description>Assessment # Assessment is an integral part of teaching and learning, forming part of the cycle of performance, evaluation, and reflection that underpins your artistic development. It is also the mechanism which allows for a judgement as to whether you have completed the requirements of the programme, and, in the case of modules which carry a grade, to what standard. Assessment involves gathering, measuring and judging information about your progress.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/attendance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/attendance/</guid><description>Attendance # You are expected to attend all classes and rehearsals. Poor attendance and/or poor timekeeping will have a detrimental impact on your learning and the learning of other students. It can also lead to disciplinary action in line with the Conservatoire&amp;rsquo;s Rules and Regulations.
Illness # Unforeseen absence due to illness should be logged on Asimut no later than 9:30am. You must not declare illness unless you are actually ill.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/grading_matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/grading_matrix/</guid><description>Grading matrix # For the postgraduate programmes in music the descriptors used in the Common Assessment Scale are supported by an Assessment Matrix (or &amp;lsquo;rubric&amp;rsquo;) that outlines what is meant at this level by &amp;rsquo;excellent&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;very good&amp;rsquo; and so on.
Performance Creativity Collaboration Research Excellent: A1-5 Technically assured, highly expressive, fully focused, highly detailed, articulate, effective, imaginative, original Boldly original, creative and intelligent work drawing on a well-founded practical and theoretical perspective Generous, imaginative, decisive and original contribution to the ensemble, project or class; sensitive collaboration with other disciplines A thorough command of the research area providing insights into complex issues.</description></item></channel></rss>